I can win!
Against Reiner, I can win!
Hey...
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Above you! Look out!
Eren!
"The Hunters"
"Trost District"
Commander.
Wake up, Commander Pyxis.
You'll get sick if you fall asleep here.
I can't believe you drank all this.
You're not young anymore.
And I'd rather not spend my days
changing your diapers.
Being cared for by a pretty lady
sounds all right to me.
So? What's the situation?
Patrols were sent out once the Titans were
gone from the 1st and 2nd defensive lines,
but any Titan sightings are few and far between.
Hmm...
If Hannes and the advance squad
followed the wall without problem,
they'll be returning any minute now.
It would mean they met the unit from
Krolva District and turned around halfway.
And they couldn't have encountered
many Titans, if any.
If there was a hole in the wall,
it would never work out like that.
Commander Pyxis.
Hmm?
Oh. If it isn't Erwin.
I hear you've captured
one of those troublesome mice.
Yes.
Unfortunately, we were one step behind.
Hmm...
But at least it will get those goons
in the interior thinking.
Maybe they'll reconsider how important
their stale beliefs and motives are to them.
Yes, it appears they have.
Look over there.
The Military Police have finally been
forced into an area with Titans.
Can't believe we didn't see any Titans.
Was there really none at all?
Seems so. It's unusually quiet out there.
I wonder if they're still alive...
Can you believe it?
I thought this was an emergency.
Yeah. And everyone's just sitting around here.
Hey, Levi. Where you hiding the Titans at?
Oh? You all seem so disappointed.
Sorry... A shame you couldn't fight Titans today.
If you're looking for another chance,
there's plenty of expeditions outside the walls.
How about we join forces
and face some Titans together?
Uh, well you know...
We're busy with work on the interior...
The advance squad's returned!
Inform Commander Pyxis!
I see...
So there was nothing wrong with the wall?
Yes, sir!
As I suspected...
H-However, there's a bit of a situation!
We were heading back to Trost to give our report
when we ran into the Scout unit
led by Section Commander Hange.
Along with them, there were recruits
from the 104th without their equipment.
And it turns out, three of them...
...were Titans!
What are you talking about?
Are you saying there were more?!
Th-Three more of them?!
Who was it?!
U-Uh, well...
Jean, relax.
What happened when their forms were revealed?
The Scouts engaged the Colossal
and Armored Titan in battle.
But by the time we joined up with them to fight...
...it was all over.
Unbelievable. What a disaster.
Luckily we were above so we got away unscathed.
Everyone underneath got blasted by steam
and wind. There's nothing they could do.
How's Mikasa doing?
I don't see any bad wounds,
so I'm guessing it's a concussion.
I see...
Armin... You haven't eaten, have you?
I'll get you something.
You've gotta eat.
"Field Rations" "An extremely nutritious ration
utilized by the Scout Regiment."
Mikasa!
Mikasa! It's Eren!
What happened to Eren?!
It's those three bullies again.
They took some bread I bought from me.
So he went on his own to get--
I tried to stop him!
Wait!
Give it back!
I thought I told you already.
There's none left 'cause I ate it.
Got it?
That was three days' worth
of food for his family!
You gotta be kidding me. Those table scraps?
Quit it, man. I feel bad now.
If you're fine with vomit, I'll give it back.
Pay him back for what you took!
Hey! Knock it off!
Hey!
You drunk, good-for-nothing soldiers!
Come and break up this fight!
Put a sock in it.
Can't you see the kids are just fooling around?
Like hell they're fooling around!
Come and stop 'em!
It'll be fine, I'm telling ya.
Someone will be along
who can help more than we can.
Huh?!
Eren!
Eat this!
It's Mikasa!
Mikasa! Why are you here?!
Eren, if you don't get home and chop wood,
your mother will get angry again.
You little... Don't underestimate me!
You asked for it!
Eren!
Let Mikasa handle this!
Yeah, right!
Nice one, Eren!
Don't lose to Mikasa!
The hell you doing?!
I told you to stop the fight,
you damn freeloaders!
What was that?!
Wanna say that again?!
Damn straight I will! You're a waste of taxes!
You son of a--!
Don't let it get to you.
It's the truth whether you like it or--
Heh.
That was a pretty good punch
for a chump who runs a stall.
Get 'em! Knock his lights out, Hannes!
You've got this!
Don't let that useless turd beat you!
Hey, you idiots! What the hell are you doing?!
--Cut it out!
--Give it back!
Damn it!
Knock it off!
Hey! This is turning pretty serious, you guys!
Forget it! Let's scram!
Wait right there!
Wait!
Eren! I don't care about the bread anymore!
Thanks for trying!
Eren. We should get back home, too.
Go home without me!
Eren!
Stop right there!
Eren! Wait!
Eren!
Mikasa?
Armin! Where's Eren?!
Mikasa, calm down!
You shouldn't be moving!
We don't know how badly you're injured!
Where is he?!
Eren was taken away.
Ymir, too, by Bertholdt and Reiner.
Eren, he...
...he lost to the Armored Titan.
It's been five hours since then.
Is anyone...
Is anyone chasing them?
No...
Why not?!
All the horses are on the other side of the wall.
In order to rescue Eren, we have to wait
for lifts to come so we can move the horses.
There's nothing we can do.
Section Commander Hange and
the other officers are too injured to move.
To even send out a small scouting party,
we're going to need more soldiers than this.
Soldiers with experience.
Understand?
Not this again...
Does it hurt somewhere?
No...
I must've hit my head pretty hard, but I'm fine.
But...
When Eren was taken away by Annie...
...I chased them right away.
And fighting alongside
Captain Levi, in the end...
...in the end, we were able to get him back.
But... if it's already been five hours...
Hey, Armin.
Why?
Why does Eren always go
somewhere far away from us?
Yeah, now that you mention it...
Eren has always run off on his own,
leaving us behind...
I guess that's just the way things
are meant to happen... for Eren at least.
But all I want... is to be at his side.
That's all I ask for...
Mikasa? So you're up, huh?
I bet you're hungry. Here, eat this.
Armin, catch.
As usual, field rations are all there is.
Hmm...
Taste neither good nor bad. Same as always.
Speaking of which,
this is the same as always, too.
Ever since the good old days, you two have
been there to clean up the mess of that brat.
That's what I call a lousy relationship. Sheesh.
It's a different time and a different place, but you
kids are doing the same thing you always have.
Am I right?
The neighborhood bullies and Titans
are a little bit different in size.
True... The thing is, that brat isn't
even all that good at fighting.
But no matter if he's up against three or five,
he'll charge in all the same.
By the time Mikasa or soldiers showed up,
he'd been beaten into a pulp every time.
But you know...
I've never seen him win a fight before, but I've
never seen him get beat and give up either.
Sometimes he's so tenacious
that even I think it's scary.
No matter how many times
he's knocked over, he gets back up.
That's the kinda guy he is.
You think he'll get taken away
without putting up a fight?
Nope. He'll keep resisting
as long as he has strength.
Even more so when he's up against just two.
He'll give 'em hell no matter who he's up against.
Until you or I show up to help.
That's how Eren's always been.
I loved those good old days.
If you ask Eren, he'd say those days
were nothing more than a false peace.
But for me, I'm more than happy
to be a drunk, useless soldier.
If it means getting back to
those plain, ordinary days...
...I'll do whatever I have to.
No matter how long it takes to get there.
I'm coming, too.
Without you three together again,
I can't bring back the good old days.
They're here!
Hey!
Isn't that...?
Commander Erwin!
And the Military Police!
I never thought they'd ride along the wall.
That's probably the quickest route.
Christa...
I'd prefer if you stayed back, but...
No matter what you say, I won't.
I refuse to wait here when Ymir was taken away.
You two should know how I feel.
Christa has a point, Armin.
We have plenty of reasons
for chasing after them.
One of which I still can't believe...
That Reiner and Bertholdt are our enemies.
I've gotta hear it straight from their mouths.
You made it, Commander Erwin!
Is the situation the same?
Yes, sir!
Good.
Deploy the lifts!
Hange?!
Moblit...
G-Gimme a map.
It might be a long shot,
but there's a giant forest here.
We should head straight for it.
Though, it's not like they have a way
to hide the Armored Titan's footsteps, but...
...I think that's where they're headed.
Why's that?
It's a gamble, but even if they have
the strength to change into Titans,
the other Titans outside
the wall might still be a threat.
Especially after all that fighting.
They might not be as bad off as Eren,
but I'm sure they're exhausted.
Like how Annie was out cold for a while.
Let's assume for now that their destination
is somewhere outside of Wall Maria.
Considering the distance they'll have to cover,
we can assume they'll need
to recover their stamina.
Which means... they'll want to rest somewhere
where Titans are unable to reach them.
At least until nightfall when Titans can't move.
Oh, Eren...
You're awake?
We have until night!
If we reach the forest before nightfall,
we still might make it in time!
Let's move!
Eren wakes up within the giant forest.
Desperate to escape, Eren attempts to
transform once again, but is stopped by Ymir.
Deep in the isolated forest, the emotions
of Eren and Reiner violently clash.
They must settle things once and for all.
Not only for themselves,
but for all those who've died.
Next episode: "Opening."